Register of the Poland. Poselstwo (Finland) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Poselstwo (Finland) records,
1919-1941
45002
Poland. Poselstwo (Finland)
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, telegrams, and memoranda, relating to Polish-Finnish relations and to Polish diplomacy during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1945
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (4 reels).
Historical Note
Polish legation in Finland.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Polish Legation in Finland (Poselstwo Rzeczposplitej Polskiej w Finlandii) were received by the Hoover Institution in 1945 and consist mainly of a large portion of the telegrams exchanged with the Foreign Ministry Headquarters in Warsaw, but also include instructions and annotated typescripts of the agreement with Finland signed in Warsaw in March 1920.
Though the telegrams cover the entire inter-war period and go up to 1941, most of them date from the 1920s, giving a good insight into the functioning of a diplomatic post in the first decade of Poland's independence.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Finland--Foreign relations--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--Finland.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Finland.; World War, 1939-1945.; Finland.
Series Description
- Agreement, 1920. (Box 1)
  Annotated typescripts of the Polish-Finnish economic, military, and political agreement signed in Warsaw in March 1920
- Telegrams, 1919-1941. (Box 1-3)
  Incoming and outgoing telegrams, arranged chronologically. Includes some correspondence and memoranda
Container List
- AGREEMENT, 1920. (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Polish-Finnish economic, military, political agreement signed in Warsaw in March 1920. Typescripts with annotations signed by representatives of both sides
- TELEGRAMS, 1919-1941.
  Includes some correspondence and memoranda
  - 1919 - Incoming and outgoing (Folder 1: 2)
  - 1920
    - General. (Folder 1: 3)
      Logbook
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 4)
    - Outgoing, January-October (Folder 1: 5)
  - 1921
    - Incoming. (Folder 1: 6)
      Typescripts
    - Incoming and outgoing, January-March, November-December. (Folder 1: 7)
    - Outgoing
      - Holographs (top secret) (Folder 1: 8)
      - Typescripts, March. (Folder 1: 9)
        Relates to the bombing of Kronstadt
  - 1922
    - Incoming.
      - Copies (Folder 1: 10)
      - Originals (Folder 1: 11)
    - Outgoing
      - General (Folder 1: 12)
      - Top secret (Folder 1: 13)
  - 1923.
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 14)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 15)
  - 1924 - Incoming and outgoing. (Box 2)
    Logbooks
    - January-June (Folder 2: 1)
    - August-December (Folder 2: 2)
  - 1925 - Incoming and outgoing. (Folder 2: 3)
  - 1926 - Incoming and outgoing.
    - January-August (Folder 2: 4)
    - August-December (Folder 2: 5)
  - 1927 - Outgoing. (Folder 2: 6)
  - 1927 February - 1930 October - Incoming and outgoing. (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - 1930 September - 1936 December - Incoming and outgoing. (Folder 3: 2)
  - 1937-1938 - Incoming and outgoing. (Folder 3: 3)
  - 1939 - Incoming and outgoing. (Folder 3: 4)
  - 1941 January-June 23 - Incoming and Outgoing. (Folder 3: 5)